Lowell Thomas Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 1. Reel-to-Reel audio tape, 1934 - 1981; 1; Boxes: 1744 - 1818
  - Subseries 1.16: Miscellany, 1.16; Boxes: 1795 - 1818
    - Nepal - Kashmir Trip, Lowell Thomas, political, Nepal R III, 1956 (Folder 1798.15, Box 1798)
      Lowell Thomas from Nepal, Reel number III Address before political group in Kathmandu (reel number 4 contains portions missed during reel changes on 15 inches per second equipment) Recorded in Kathmandu
    - Nepal - Kashmir Trip, Lowell Thomas, political, Nepal R IV, 1956 (Folder 1798.16, Box 1798)
      Lowell Thomas from Nepal, Reel IV Address before political group at Kathmandu This tape is at 7.5 inches per second made as a stand-by tape during reel changes. The original tapes are recorded at 15 inches per second. This tape will have to be changed to that speed before it is “edited in.” Recorded in Nepal
    - Nepal - Kashmir Trip, Lowell Thomas from Kathmandu, Nepal, 1956 (Folder 1798.17, Box 1798)
      Lowell Thomas from Kashmir Number 31 - Danger of Communist using Nepal as gateway to India - K.I. Singh, possible Communist member - visits King, talks to Prime Minister “Acharya” Agrees Communism is possible in Nepal. U.S. must help to prevent. Bird sound effects follows Recorded in Oberoi Palace Hotel, Kashmir
    - Lowell Thomas from Nepal, 1970 (Folder 1798.18, Box 1798)
      8 pieces, rough cut Heart transplant, retraction :55 Winter in Alaska 1:05 Liddell Hart 1:21 Moses 1:57 Church 1:32 Jobs 1:57 Gorilla 2:08 State 2:05
    - Lowell Thomas from Nepal, 1970 (Folder 1799.01, Box 1799)
      Lowell Thomas copy or original, 2 pieces, rough cut, Nepal 1970, Latter-Day Lincoln, Dereham: 1:22, Elephants: 1:50
    - Nepal, undated (Folder 1799.02, Box 1799)
      Volume 3
    - Return to Nepal, undated (Folder 1799.03, Box 1799)
    - New Guinea Expedition, 1963 June 5 (Folder 1799.04, Box 1799)
      Lowell Thomas 1) event - New Guinea - number 1 2) New Guinea - number 2 3) New Guinea - number 3 4) New Guinea - number 4 5) New Guinea -number 5 6) New Guinea - number 6 Contents transferred to Dictaphone and typed - 6-5-63 at Pawling, New York
    - Lowell Thomas from New Guinea, 1963, 1963 June 12 (Folder 1799.05, Box 1799)
      1. Chief Ningi 2. Closes…”whenever they come to the spirit house in time of calamity to pray 3. [Hard copy of script attached; filed elsewhere]
    - Lowell Thomas from New Guinea, 1963, 1963 June 14 (Folder 1799.06, Box 1799)
      New Guinea number 6
    - Lowell Thomas from New Guinea, 1963, 1963 June 18 (Folder 1799.07, Box 1799)
      New Guinea number 8
    - Lowell Thomas from New Guinea, 1963, 1963 June 17 (Folder 1799.08, Box 1799)
      New Guinea number 7
    - Lowell Thomas from New Guinea, 1963, 1963 June 19 (Folder 1799.09, Box 1799)
      New Guinea number 9
    - Lowell Thomas from New Guinea, undated (Folder 1799.10, Box 1799)
      On Pidgin English Future of New Guinea “Latter of Success”
    - Lowell Thomas from New Guinea, undated (Folder 1799.11, Box 1799)
      Lowell Thomas of George Ellis - Sepik River District
    - Lowell Thomas from New Guinea, undated (Folder 1799.12, Box 1799)
      Residue from edited tapes
    - Rickenbacker memorial service part number 1, 1973 August 7 (Folder 1799.13, Box 1799)
    - Rickenbacker Memorial Service, 1973 August 7 (Folder 1799.14, Box 1799)
      Part number 2
    - Captain Eddie Rickenbacker Memorial Service, 1973 August 7 (Folder 1799.15, Box 1799)
    - Prayer Tower Presentation - Oral Roberts University, undated (Folder 1799.16, Box 1799)
    - Salute to Lowell Thomas, circa 1970 (Folder 1799.17, Box 1799)
      WDBO Orlando, Florida; February 5; 40th year of broadcasting; Fred Bradshaw WDBO Radio News Director; Travel Films and Lectures, unusual news; broadcast excerpts, interviews; bloopers
    - Schooner Bowdoin, undated (Folder 1800.01, Box 1800)
    - Squaw Valley Revisited, undated (Folder 1800.02, Box 1800)
      Lowell Thomas and Alec Cushing
    - Squaw Valley Revisited, undated (Folder 1800.03, Box 1800)
    - Squaw Valley Revisited, undated (Folder 1800.04, Box 1800)
    - Max Thornburg memoirs I, undated (Folder 1800.05, Box 1800)
      1. Mr. Max Thornburg memoirs 2. Questions by Lowell Thomas 3. Recorded in Pawling, New York studios
    - Max Thornburg memoirs II, undated (Folder 1800.06, Box 1800)
      1. Mr. Max Thornburg memoirs 2. Questions by Lowell Thomas 3. Recorded at Pawling, New York studio
    - Max Thornburg memoirs III, undated (Folder 1800.07, Box 1800)
    - Max Thornburg memoirs IV, undated (Folder 1800.08, Box 1800)
    - Max Thornburg memoirs V, undated (Folder 1800.09, Box 1800)
    - Max Thornburg memoirs VI, undated (Folder 1800.10, Box 1800)
    - Yangona Ceremoney, undated (Folder 1800.11, Box 1800)
      Meke, Isa Ley, original, reel 2
    - Yangona Ceremony, undated (Folder 1800.12, Box 1800)
      Original, reel 1
    - Yagona Ceremony, undated (Folder 1800.13, Box 1800)
      Meke, Isa Ley Tail end - white [paper] marks beginning of a [juice]; yellow = the end Dupe
    - Lowell Thomas -broadcasts, circa 1930s (Folder 1801.01, Box 1801)
      September 29, 1930 - introduction to Lowell Thomas by Ed Thorgensen, Lowell Thomas’s first broadcast for Literary Digest (from three records) May 25, 1936 - Lowell Thomas news with musical interpolation test record (WIZ New York) May 28, 1936 - (reverse of below) - Lowell Thomas news, Clyde Catell for Sonoco June 1, 1936 - Lowell Thomas news, Clyde Catell for Sonoco July 29, 1936 - M. Hoover, 60th birthday
    - Lowell Thomas, 1940 October 30 (Folder 1801.02, Box 1801)
      Endless Cavern (original)
    - Lowell Thomas -Cut #5, 1952 (Folder 1801.03, Box 1801)
      Tape #4
    - Lowell Thomas - Hershey 13 Oct. 1953, 1953 October (Folder 1801.04, Box 1801)
      Location: Hershey, PA Laugh sequence - “with and without nuts”
    - Lowell Thomas -from Japan, 1952 (Folder 1801.05, Box 1801)
      Etsuko Watanabe Ceremony of Old Japan Numb from Jet Travel Geisha General MacArthur as the greatest man of all time Joe Robinson Tokyo Fireworks Visit with Emperor Revolution in Tibet Hints at another Tibet Trip 10/30/52
    - Lowell Thomas, circa 1958 April 3 (Folder 1801.06, Box 1801)
      Lowell Thomas program for Delco 1) Dalai Lama flight 2) Ike’s address 3) Moscow and press 4) Akahito Wedding 5) Soviet-Mexico mêlée 6) Artificial satellite Don Morrow, ANNC. Recorded at KNX April 3, 1958(?)
    - Lowell Thomas - for Tom Murphy and Trenton, 1961 November 12 (Folder 1801.07, Box 1801)
      1. Recorded on Ampex 2. Pawling, New York
    - Lowell Thomas - for L.P.C., 1962 May 14 (Folder 1801.08, Box 1801)
      1. Copy - Toni Matt
    - undated (Folder 1801.09, Box 1801)
      Lowell Thomas vs. Rivers number 1
    - Lowell Thomas, 1962 December 7 (Folder 1801.10, Box 1801)
      Lowell Thomas vs. Rivers number 2; (duped December 7, 1962)
    - Lowell Thomas - “Adventure”, 1963 July 18 (Folder 1801.11, Box 1801)
      Recorded for KCBS San Francisco
    - Lowell Thomas - for SABC broadcast “Opinion” on October 20, 1963, 1963 October 16 (Folder 1801.12, Box 1801)
      South African Broadcasting Corporation Recorded at Cape Town Introduction, Ralph Elliot Lowell Thomas regarding T. E. Lawrence
    - Lowell Thomas - as broadcast on ABC Stations “Opinion, 1963 October 16 (Folder 1801.13, Box 1801)
      South African Broadcasting Corporation “Monday at Eight” by Ralph Elliot Recorded at Cape Town Report on American Antarctic flight before take-off from Cape Town, broadcast September 30, 1963, 8:36 Report on American Antarctic flight on completion. (From McMurdo Sound), broadcast October 7, 1963, 7:55 Comment by Lowell Thomas on his life following World War I, broadcast October 14, 1963, 5:54
    - Lowell Thomas - from Moscow, 1963 October 28 (Folder 1801.14, Box 1801)
      Regarding South Polar flight 2 pieces
    - Lowell Thomas - talks on skiing, 1963 (Folder 1801.15, Box 1801)
      Recorded at ski chalet, Strawberry Hill, Pawling New York
    - Lowell Thomas - reports to Alaska from New York, 1965 (Folder 1801.16, Box 1801)
      (via phone) RTW flight, Austin and Finch
    - Lowell Thomas - for Miss Jane Barton, program director. A Salute to American school teachers, 1965 April 12 (Folder 1801.17, Box 1801)
      R-TV-MP Bureau. New York State Department of Commerce. Retake made 4-12-65
    - Lowell Thomas - recording from “Party Line”, 1966 September 21 (Folder 1801.18, Box 1801)
      WCCO Radio in Minneapolis, Minnesota. Guest on “Party Line” with Charlie Boone and Roger Erickson From Gordon A. Mikkelson, Director Program Promotions and Public Relations 625 2nd Avenue, Pawling, New York 612-332-1202 September 5, 1966, October 10, 1966
    - Lowell Thomas, 1967 December (Folder 1802.01, Box 1802)
      Lowell Thomas and Electra; Laugh Sequence, regular CBS program. “Fartheart” started it all. Tape blank following “system”
    - Lowell Thomas - “Today”, 1968 (Folder 1802.02, Box 1802)
      Flight book Regular program Lotem Jerusalem “Shorties” Musical introduction to Lowell Thomas House of Lords introduction to Lowell Thomas Easter seals for KSL
    - Lowell Thomas - narrating Dut. Co. United Fund film, 1968 (Folder 1802.03, Box 1802)
      1. Into to Phillip Hansen - Lowell Thomas 2. Lowell Thomas into to Phillip Hansen’s story on Lawrence of Arabia 3. LT promotion for KFMB San Diego 5/31/68
    - Lowell Thomas - for Aviation Hall of Fame, 1968 (Folder 1802.04, Box 1802)
      J.E. Condron, Executive Director 1. Sikorsky 2. McGrady 3. Byrd 4. Earhart Recorded at Pawling, NY Studios
    - Lowell Thomas - promotions, 1968 (Folder 1802.05, Box 1802)
      For Dick Noel at WJOY Burlington, VT 1. Ski safety tips 2. Ike Obit 3. Abu Simbel-Wallace 4. “Food for the World” 5. Niagara University news except for program 10/68
    - Lowell Thomas, 1969 February 17 (Folder 1802.06, Box 1802)
      Lowell Thomas and Mike Wallace; Lowell Thomas and Gene for Mike Wallace Games portion edited out for final tape
    - Lowell Thomas, 1969 February 17 (Folder 1802.07, Box 1802)
      Lowell Thomas and Gene for Mike Wallace Program; Flight book promotion Pawling
    - Lowell Thomas, 1969 February 18 (Folder 1802.08, Box 1802)
      Bernt Balchen Air service post 501 A and R recording, inc.
    - Lowell Thomas - moon - space story, 1969 July 15 (Folder 1802.09, Box 1802)
    - Lowell Thomas - on The Johnny Carson Show…, 1969 (Folder 1802.10, Box 1802)
      June 25, 1969 Compliments: Tony Janak
    - Lowell Thomas, 1969 (Folder 1802.11, Box 1802)
      Lowell Thomas and Alec Cushing; Squaw Valley Re-visited; Lowell Thomas en route around world; 1 room for Mr. Guihe [?] 1. Sequoia 2. Tanker Mountain [Lanker?] 3. Trivia 4. Rain (Hawaii) 5. September 3, 1969
    - Lowell Thomas - for Fred Turner, 1970 January 1 (Folder 1802.12, Box 1802)
    - Lowell Thomas, 1970 March 3 (Folder 1802.13, Box 1802)
    - Lowell Thomas, 1970 October 20 (Folder 1802.14, Box 1802)
      Broadcast, Master, Lowell Thomas 40th year
    - Lowell Thomas - Mike Wallace (Folder 1802.15, Box 1802)
      1. Television - CBS
    - Lowell Thomas, 1971 March 16 (Folder 1802.16, Box 1802)
      As requested by Julie Broadcast of Tuesday, March 16, contains Lowell Thomas story on Governor Thomas E. Dewey
    - Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 1802.17, Box 1802)
      1. NBC television
    - Lowell Thomas, 1971 October 28 (Folder 1802.18, Box 1802)
      From Rome October 28, 1971
    - Lowell Thomas - tapes used during Europe Trip, 1971 October (Folder 1803.01, Box 1803)
    - Lowell Thomas, 1971 November (Folder 1803.02, Box 1803)
      Mike Douglas TV show Tony [Vanak]
    - Lowell Thomas, 1971 November (Folder 1803.03, Box 1803)
    - Lowell Thomas, 1971 (Folder 1803.04, Box 1803)
      Lowell Thomas on Queen Elizabeth 1st Show 10/14/71
    - Lowell Thomas - Birthday Dinner, 1972 April 6 (Folder 1803.05, Box 1803)
      Contemporary Hotel, Disney World, Orlando, Part 2 Played for Lowell Thomas 5-1-72
    - Lowell Thomas, 1972 March 9 (Folder 1803.06, Box 1803)
    - Lowell Thomas, 1972 (Folder 1803.07, Box 1803)
      Lowell Thomas Birthday Story 4/14/72
    - Lowell Thomas - Variety Club, 1973 February 14 (Folder 1803.08, Box 1803)
      Number 2, Lowell Thomas address to end of program, reel 2 of 2
    - Lowell Thomas - Larry Glick, 1973 May 18 (Folder 1803.09, Box 1803)
      Mr. Lowell Thomas via Kenny Meyers
    - Lowell Thomas - Columbia University, 1973 December 13 (Folder 1803.10, Box 1803)
      Unedited
    - Lowell Thomas, Pawling, 1974 May 8 (Folder 1803.11, Box 1803)
    - Lowell Thomas - Capital Cities, 1974 May 9 (Folder 1803.12, Box 1803)
    - Lowell Thomas - with Dave McElhatton, 1974 June 29 (Folder 1803.13, Box 1803)
      KCBS San Francisco “So Long Everybody”
    - Lowell Thomas - 45th anniversary (Radio), 1975 September 26-29 (Folder 1803.14, Box 1803)
      1. Lowell Thomas news 9/29/75 2. World Tonight - Dough Edwards 9/29/75 3. News break - Charles Osgood 9/27/75 4. Paul Harvey News 9/26/75
    - Lowell Thomas, 1976 May 14 (Folder 1803.15, Box 1803)
      A Tribute to Lowell Thomas Dave McElhatton
    - Lowell Thomas, 1976 January 7 (Folder 1803.16, Box 1803)
    - Lowell Thomas, 1976 March 19 (Folder 1803.17, Box 1803)
      Pacific Pioneer Broadcasters Luncheon honoring Lowell Thomas, Sportsman Lodge, Los Angeles, California
    - Lowell Thomas, 1977 March (Folder 1803.18, Box 1803)
      Afghanistan talks about Kabul embassy
    - Lowell Thomas - from Moscow, undated (Folder 1804.01, Box 1804)
      #4
    - Lowell Thomas - cut #4, Peno Air, undated (Folder 1804.02, Box 1804)
      8 minutes with Captain Dent Terrell on PHH Stratocruiser Recorded August 21st Edited and spliced 9/27/52
    - Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 1804.03, Box 1804)
      Hold for F. Turner 3/5/70 3/6/70
    - Lowell Thomas - broadcast and fireside chat, undated (Folder 1804.04, Box 1804)
      1. Recorded by WLAD, Danbury, Connecticut at Quaker Hill Country Club 2. Poor quality possibly due to twin track recording 3. Nine Old Men origins (live audience)
    - Lowell Thomas - en route to Australia, undated (Folder 1804.05, Box 1804)
      Lowell Thomas en route to Alaska via New Hebrides, New Guinea Ross Smith - Pilot - was prize for being first to fly England to Australia Same as 1762.03
    - Lowell Thomas - en route to Asia, undated (Folder 1804.06, Box 1804)
      Peter Freuchen Seven Seas phrase
    - Lowell Thomas - from Kathmandu on Israel, undated (Folder 1804.07, Box 1804)
      (for Electra) Main speaker: Lowell Thomas; Galilee, Golan Heights
    - Lowell Thomas - reports on Bernt Balchen, undated (Folder 1804.08, Box 1804)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, other speakers: Bernt Balchen, speaks on Greenland
    - Lowell Thomas - Larry Beck and Lowell Thomas on Pherbia Project, undated (Folder 1804.09, Box 1804)
      Recorded for Lowell Thomas: From Alaska; copy also sent to Thornburgs; Pherbia Project; Robert Service exhibit; Eskimo dresses; [later becomes unusable then gets better]
    - Lowell Thomas - Recorded Letter to D. Warren McCormick, undated (Folder 1804.10, Box 1804)
      South Africa; man who received 266,000 telegrams in response to a single broadcast, Lowell Thomas actually received 265,567 telegrams, largest response to any broadcast, freak incident, Admiral Richard E. Byrd Arctic Expedition with Russell Owen, Owen broadcasted through Littleton, New Zealand, Newcomb Carlton of Western Union, announcer Jimmy Wallington, offered free telegrams to Lowell Thomas, some confused listeners sent telegrams from Postal, a competitor, two thousand telegrams were repeats from May West; was given a live bear for Christmas, kept for awhile then given to a Zoo, jet lag from South Pole16:10
    - Lowell Thomas - chat, undated (Folder 1804.11, Box 1804)
      Lowell Thomas Chats Chats with Live Audience at Grand Canyon April 11th, 1968
    - Lowell Thomas - Darwin number 1 to number 4, undated (Folder 1804.12, Box 1804)
      Spool number 1 - end out. Recorded on Nagra III NP63 machine at 7 ½ inches per second. Line up tone at -40b on Nagra PPM. Some print through may be evident.
    - Lowell Thomas - laughter record, undated (Folder 1804.13, Box 1804)
      Copy of Walter Cronkite; Xmas Carol “as per your request;” Dolly Dimple blooper and laugh; Joke record with prank phone calls
    - Lowell Thomas - on General Motors Corporation, undated (Folder 1804.14, Box 1804)
      Lowell Thomas on GM, General Motors, President Ed Cole
    - Lowell Thomas - 9&10, undated (Folder 1804.15, Box 1804)
      Thomas Broadcast Attn. Electra Boris Father Moran
    - Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 1804.16, Box 1804)
      LT Tape - re Joe Kirkwood
    - Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 1804.17, Box 1804)
      2 Unknown Lowell Thomas Recordings 1 - 3:32 2 - 3:01
    - Lowell Thomas - Botany at Sikkim, undated (Folder 1804.18, Box 1804)
      1. Sonny Kumar story 2. Story of Tibet-British fight 3. Maharajia 4. Young husband 5. Lowell Thomas at Chungu - Mule song 6. Note: To Taylor, Stanton, Prosper - Regarding stations wanting records
    - Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 1805.01, Box 1805)
      1. Lowell Thomas, Jr. on talks with officials 2. Lowell Thomas, Sr., on Tashi Lama
    - Lowell Thomas - 50th anniversary, undated (Folder 1805.02, Box 1805)
      As a Law student - Chicago Kent College of Law
    - Lowell Thomas - feeds, undated (Folder 1805.03, Box 1805)
      1. CBS Radio 2. Safety copy
    - Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 1805.04, Box 1805)
      Abu Dhabi
    - Lowell Thomas - S.P. 5 and 6, undated (Folder 1805.05, Box 1805)
    - Lowell Thomas - Founders Day - “Dub” (Folder 1805.06, Box 1805)
    - Lowell Thomas - broadcast from Hawaii, undated (Folder 1805.07, Box 1805)
      1. Gene: Here are three tapes for December 23, 24, and 25. Two more will follow on the next mail 2. For Monday, December 3 - Sanskrit 3. For Tuesday, December 4 - Cardinal Spellman 4. For Wednesday, December 25 - Australia Oil
    - Lowell Thomas - on South Africa, undated (Folder 1805.08, Box 1805)
    - Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 1805.09, Box 1805)
      1. Reel 1
    - Lowell Thomas - for John Jay, undated (Folder 1805.10, Box 1805)
      1. Ski recollections 2. Recorded on Bell 3. Pawling Studios
    - Lowell Thomas - Number 5, India, undated (Folder 1805.11, Box 1805)
    - Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 1805.12, Box 1805)
      1) Siberian Trip 2) National Parks 3) Maharajah Story 4) Rose Red City of Tetra 5) An Automologist
    - Lowell Thomas - Fitzmaurice laugh sequence, undated (Folder 1805.13, Box 1805)
      Hershey “nuts”
    - Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 1805.14, Box 1805)
      Poems by Lowell Thomas
    - Lowell Thomas - regarding museum, undated (Folder 1805.15, Box 1805)
      [Olive Gunnison?]
    - Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr., undated (Folder 1805.16, Box 1805)
      1. Reel 2
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. over South Pole, undated (Folder 1805.17, Box 1805)
      1. Reel 3
    - Lowell Thomas - Composite 2, undated (Folder 1806.01, Box 1806)
    - Lowell Thomas - Composite 4, undated (Folder 1806.02, Box 1806)
    - Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 1806.03, Box 1806)
      Unknown Lowell Thomas Special
    - Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr., undated (Folder 1806.04, Box 1806)
      1. Reel 4, November 16
    - Canon Joseph E. Fison, 1956 June 10 (Folder 1806.05, Box 1806)
      Sunday June 10, 1956
    - Los Angeles Town Hall, 1957 July 30 (Folder 1806.06, Box 1806)
    - Dedication ceremonies, 1959 October 7 (Folder 1806.07, Box 1806)
      1. 10th Mt. Div. Tennessee Pass [10th Mountain Division] 2. Recorded from original, employing all distortion and levels 3. Mr. Minot Dole Ward Howell Associates Inc. 122 East 42nd Street, New York, New York
    - School, 1960 December 9 (Folder 1806.08, Box 1806)
    - Bristol-Myers “Vitalis” program, 1961 June 29 (Folder 1806.09, Box 1806)
      1. January 10, 1938 2. “For Men Only” 3. Fred Vitell, M.C. 4. Featuring Keenan Wynn, Lowell Thomas, Jr., Otto Horback, Rudolph Fremel, Elliot Roosevelt
    - Salute to Lake Placid, 1961 (Folder 1806.10, Box 1806)
      1. From Squaw Valley 2. Lake Placid 1932/1960 3. Winter Olympics
    - Bishop Welsh, 1962 November 6 (Folder 1806.11, Box 1806)
    - Menoa[?], 1963 January 11 (Folder 1806.12, Box 1806)
      Contents Unknown
    - A Report on “Current” Tee, 1963 January 29 (Folder 1806.13, Box 1806)
      WBBM, Chicago. (1963). Recorded from Williamstown Inn via phone. Lowell Thomas’s report on Lawrence of Arabia
    - CBS News Special, 1963 October 3 (Folder 1806.14, Box 1806)
      1. Lowell Thomas from Australia via S.W. “Epsom Handicap” Ready and Crew, October 5, 1963 - not used on air 2. Lowell Thomas reports on historic flight from Cape Town, South Africa to McMurdo Sound, Antarctic
    - Report from Mrs. K. K. Cantwell on Tibetans, 1963 (Folder 1807.01, Box 1807)
      1. Interview with Secretary Hodges at South Pole
    - Mr. Lee Robinson from Australia, 1964 June 5 (Folder 1807.02, Box 1807)
      “Garden of Eden Sermon” as given by missionary in New Guinea in pidgin English.
    - Olive M. Gunnison, 1964 August 5 (Folder 1807.03, Box 1807)
      1. Talk on museum
    - “Winter Sports Conference”, 1964 October 19 (Folder 1807.04, Box 1807)
      1. Part I 2. Woodstock, Vermont 3. Toni Matt speech 4. Quality below broadcast standards but audible
    - Winter Sports Conference, 1964 October 19 (Folder 1807.05, Box 1807)
      1. Part 2 2. Woodstock, Vermont 3. Also Toni Matt speech 4. Quality below broadcast standards but audible
    - Norwegian Tape, 1965 July 14 (Folder 1807.06, Box 1807)
      Odyssey Productions, Olaf and Lars 1) Narration: Finn Ronne, stories July 14, 1965 (original 7.5 inches per second ¼ track) 2) Narration: Finn Ronne at South Pole PQ 7.5 inches per second (original 3.75 inches per second ¼ track, side 2 - original poor quality)
    - “Correspondents Nite”, 1965 (Folder 1807.07, Box 1807)
      1. Quaker Hill Country Club 2. Lowell Thomas chats regarding fireplace stones
    - Maynard M. Miller, 1966 March 7 (Folder 1807.08, Box 1807)
      “Every man has his Mount Everest.” Recorded at WKAR 3-7-66. Headliner Ser. MSU Evening College, Lansing, Michigan, 1 7/8 inches per second Opens: “Ladies and Gentlemen” Closes: “…tis not what man does that exalts him, but what man would do…Thank you.”
    - Paddy Appleseed, sorry, Gardenseed, tells of trip to Tibet with Lowell Thomas, 1967 February 27 (Folder 1807.09, Box 1807)
      1. Joe Pyne Show 2. Saladamalarky 3. As aired over WEOK, Poughkeepsie, New York 4. Tape courtesy of Mr. Ghine, program manager. on request
    - Dan Smith, 1968 April 1 (Folder 1807.10, Box 1807)
      Lowell Thomas Salute
    - Zharios, 1968 July 4 (Folder 1807.11, Box 1807)
      12 cuts Inserts for 12 shows while Lowell Thomas is on trip
    - Apollo 11 Capsule, circa 1968 (Folder 1807.12, Box 1807)
      1. Two tracks turn over 3 3/6”
    - Charles A. Lindbergh - Biography, circa 1968 (Folder 1807.13, Box 1807)
      1. For: Lowell Thomas From: Tony Janak 2. Columbia Recording Studios 49 East 52nd Street New York, New York 3. Reference Recording
    - North Pole Expeditions, 1969 March 10 (Folder 1807.14, Box 1807)
      1. Recording of talk by Donald B. MacMillan about Robert Peary and North Pole discovery 2. Pawling Studios, G.E. Nicks
    - Original September 1969, 1969 September (Folder 1807.15, Box 1807)
    - In contact: With Hal Youngblood, 1969 April 20 (Folder 1807.16, Box 1807)
      Broadcast Sunday April 20, 1969 Guest: Lowell Thomas
    - Irene Wicker - The Singing Lady, 1969 August 3 (Folder 1807.17, Box 1807)
      WNYC - AM and FM Lowell Thomas and Indian Legend of The First Rainbow Copy made of tape
    - Guthe Museum, 1969 September (Folder 1807.18, Box 1807)
      1. Made by Lowell Thomas at KCBS 2. Sequential copy